Kalpana Kumari (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer - Application Programming, Seeking Roles in Software Development, Software Designing, Coding, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Testing, Application Support



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Current Company: Yantriks India pvt Itd Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Gurgaon, Delhi / NCR

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer - Application Programming, Software Developer, Software Development, Software Designing, Coding, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Testing, Application Support, Technical Support, Network

Administration, Incident Management, java, Spring

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 19-Dec-20 Last Active: 19-Dec-20

Summary

5+ Years of experience in Java surrounding Technologies space.

Kalpana is an experienced Java developer with more than 5 years of experience.

Kalpana has deep experience with Core Java Concepts (Core java, Spring Boot, Servlets),

Kalpana has worked in Java Byte code Instrumentation and multi threading.

Worked on various solution developments with proven abilities on different opportunities as and when required. Excellent interpersonal and team skills, desire to learn and implement new technologies.

Work Experience

Yantriks India pvt Itd as Senior Software Engineer Sep 2019 to Till Date

Cavisson System Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer - Application Programming Jul 2015 to Jul 2015

Cavisson System Pvt Ltd, Noida India July 2015 - Till now Software Engineer

1. Product: Netstorm and Nsecom (July 2015 - Jan 2016)

Description: Using NetDiagnostics, a JAVA application is instrumented using Byte Code Instrumentation (BCI) so that events such as a new method encountered, method entry, exit etc. can be captured to be processed later to derive the drill down reports. Such reports may be utilize to identify and thus rectify any performance issues in the application. Using Netstorm, Load testing and performance of web applications.

Responsibilities

Actively participated in Designing of the Netdiagnostics Modules.

Java coding and data base objects to handle the fetched data.

Implemented many services used by clients for supporting by Netdiagnostics

Support was provided for the application on day to day. Responding to user gueries for validation of exception.

Providing support in Java-agent to profile RMI ,JMS, SOAP calls.

Worked on Cassandra Database .

Environment: Core Java 1.7, MySql, Eclipse, Weblogic, Apache Tomcat, Servlet, Web Services (SOAP, RMI, JMS), ASM.

July 2015 - Till now Cavisson System Pvt Ltd, Noida India Software Engineer

Jan 2016 - Jan 2017 2. Product: Machine Agent (Java Based Agent)

Description: BCI Agent is a Internal Profiling tool to diagnose the response time of web application built on java. Using BCIAgent, a java based application is instrumented so that events such as a new method encountered, method entry, exit etc. can be captured to be processed later to derive the drill down reports. Such reports may be utilize to identify and thus rectify any performance issues in the application. BCIAgent provides simple and intuitive view of live application traffic and all contextual analysis germane to the monitoring and diagnostics. Following makes BCIAgent, the most advanced APM (Application Performance Management) offering:

End-to-end business transaction-centric monitoring and diagnostics

Comprehensive system level as well as service level monitoring

Deep diagnostics up to code / method level root cause analysis

Powerful dashboard features with an exclusive executive dashboard for business KPI monitoring

Big-data analytics, analyze millions of metrics, focus on those which matter .

Responsibilities

Actively participated in Designing of the agent.

Core java coding and Instrumentation using ASM Byte Code to find response time .

Implemented many services like Http Rest API ,Redis ,Mongo ,Socket.io ,Net used by clients for supporting by BCIAgent. Support was provided for the application on day to day. Responding to user queries for validation of exception.

Environment: Redis ,JMX, Apache CXF, Soap Services ,Rest API ,Socket.io , ATG , Weblogic,Spring,hibernate.

Cavisson System Pvt Ltd, Noida India July 2015 - Till now Software Engineer

3. Product: Netdiagnostics (April 2016 - Till now)

Business Transcations

CPU Profiling: NDAgent is a CPU intensive application so to track CPU issues, CPU profiling tool is added in agent using java ThreadMXBean API.

HeapDump: This addon helps to track all segments of Heap. The heap is a memory segment used to store objects, strings and closures. This is where all the magic happens.

Auto-Instrumentation

Feature by which agent should digged out hot methods causing high response time for web application. Using Instrumentation, Agent should be able to provide other drill down reports on the basis of hotspots And Cpu response graph.

Environment: Thread API, Java String API, Wrapper Classes and MultiThreading.

Education

UG: B.Sc (Chemistry) from St. Xavier College in 2012

PG: MCA (Computers) from Banasthali University in 2015

IT Skills

Core java, servlets, jsp, bash 1.7 2019 4 Year(s) 0 Mon Socket.IO , ASM , Instrumentation, Java 1.7 2018 3 Year(s) 0 Mon	
	th(s)
Dealers Claud Farm do Falina	th(s)
Docker, Cloud Foundry, Eclipse	
Redis, MySQL , Oracle , DB2	

Git, CVS, Bugzilla, Visual studio code			
LINUX, OS X and Windows.	16.1	2019	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
spring boot and Hibernate	2.4	2019	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert			
ENGLISH	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Netdiagnostics Client: Kohls ,macys,jcpenny,Gc Nature of Employment: Full Time

Role: Programmer

Skill Used: Core Java, Linux,docker Role Description: Software developer

Project Details: Adding Jms Capturing, Hotspot And cpu Capturing, dockers Implementation In Product

Project Title: ND Agent Client: Kohls.com

Duration: Jul 2015 - Jan 2016 Nature of Employment: Full Time Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Programmer

Team Size: 3

Team Size: 6

Duration: Jan 2016 - Jan 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: Core Java and ASM Byte Code

Project Details: Instrumentation, DB Queries, Http Calls And Webservice (Rest And Soap) Monitoring Capablites In Agent

Project Title: Text Normalisation

Client: Cdac Noida

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2015 - Jul 2015 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Project Location: Noida

Team Size: 2 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: Core Java

Project Details: A Project For NLP DEPT For Hindi Text Normalization

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time